skillcrush.com 2016-05-09

# Privacy Policy | Skillcrush

## Updated October 10, 2012

Skillcrush, Inc. and its respective successors and assigns (“Skillcrush,” “we,” “us” or “our”) welcomes you. Skillcrush’s mission is to make learning about technology accessible. Skillcrush maintains a website and subdomains at skillcrush.com (collectively, the “Skillcrush Site”) in furtherance of its mission. This Online Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) describes the types of personal, financial and other information that we gather from visitors who use or access the web content, products, technology and services provided by Skillcrush and available on the Skillcrush Site (collectively, the “Skillcrush Services”) and how we use the information that we gather. Please carefully read the Privacy Policy before accessing the Skillcrush Services as it applies to all persons and entities who use or access the Skillcrush Services, including you (each a “User”), and constitutes an agreement between you and Skillcrush. By accessing the Skillcrush Services, you signify that you have read the Privacy Policy and agree to be bound by it and the Skillcrush Terms of Use Agreement (“Terms”) available at <http://skillcrush.com/skillcrush-terms-of-use/>, as well as any applicable laws and regulations. We may update the Privacy Policy from time to time. Each time you use any of the Skillcrush Services, the current version of the Privacy Policy will apply. Accordingly, when you use the Skillcrush Services, you should check the date of the Privacy Policy (which appears at the top) and review any changes. If you do not agree with the Privacy Policy, you may not access or otherwise use the Skillcrush Services.

### Overview on Collection and Sharing of Information

The Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to Skillcrush through the Skillcrush Services. It does not apply to information that Skillcrush may have obtained through other means.

Information that we gather from Users falls into two broad categories: Personal Data and Aggregate Data.

### Opting Out of Certain Communications

Users are given the choice to opt-out of certain optional communications from us and our affiliates and marketing partners at the time of creating a User Profile. Users may also opt-out of the communications at any time by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link located in the communications. Users should allow a reasonable amount of time for the opt-out request to be processed. Please be aware that your opt-out choice may mean that certain features and functions of the Skillcrush Services will no longer be available to you. However, so long as you are a Skillcrush registered user, Skillcrush may need to contact you from time to time and as a Skillcrush User, you cannot opt-out of those communications that are necessary to provide the Skillcrush Services.

### Disclosures to a Successor-in-Interest

We may disclose your Personal Data and Aggregate Data to a third party as part of a reorganization or a sale of the assets or stock of Skillcrush. Any third party to which we transfer or sell Skillcrush assets or stock will have the right to continue to use the Personal Data and Aggregate Data that you provide to us, subject to this Privacy Policy as may be amended.

### Links to Other Websites

The Skillcrush Services contain links to websites operated by other people, companies or organizations. The Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third party sites, which may have their own privacy policies or no privacy policy at all. Skillcrush does not control the content of third party sites and takes no responsibility for their content, nor should it be implied that Skillcrush endorses or otherwise recommends such sites or the products or services offered. We encourage you to review the privacy policies and terms of use of any third party sites or services before providing any of them with any of your Personal Information. This Privacy Policy applies only to the Skillcrush Services.

**Authorize.net.** Authorize.net may be accessed through the Skillcrush Services to pay for certain Skillcrush Services. The authorize.net site may maintain the look and feel of the Skillcrush Site. Nonetheless your use of authorize.net or any other third party vendor that is accessible by or through the Skillcrush Services is governed by that vendor’s policies and not those of Skillcrush. It is your responsibility to review the relevant privacy policies prior to accessing the services available on such vendor sites.

### Changes to Privacy Policy

We will post material changes to this Privacy Policy here at least ten (10) business days before they take effect. Any information we collect under the current Privacy Policy will remain subject to the terms of this Policy, until you accept the new Privacy Policy by accessing or using the Skillcrush Services after the changes take effect.

### Security

Skillcrush uses a variety of safeguards to protect your personal information. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot ensure or warrant its absolute security. Consequently, when you transmit your Personal Data to us, you do so at your own risk. We use physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards and other appropriate measures to protect your Personal Data against unauthorized access or use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss.

If you create a User account, your account information will be password protected. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your login information, password and to your computer. Be sure to log off from the Skillcrush Services when finished using a shared computer. We strongly request you not to communicate any confidential information to Skillcrush through email or any other means.

If Skillcrush learns of a security systems breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using the Skillcrush Services or providing Personal Data to us, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security and privacy issues related to the Skillcrush Services. Skillcrush will endeavor to provide notice to you of any security systems breach and efforts to restore the integrity of the Skillcrush Services in accordance with applicable law. If you become aware of any breach of data security or have any other questions about the security of the Skillcrush Services, please contact us at: [hello@skillcrush.com](mailto:hello@skillcrush.com).

### Collection and Sharing of Personal Data

Personal Data is information that could reasonably be used to identify you, such as your name, address, email address, birth date, financial information, telephone number or any combination of the foregoing (“Personal Data”). We use Personal Data to provide you with Skillcrush Services that you have requested. By voluntarily providing Personal Data, you consent to the collection and use of your Personal Data in accordance with the Privacy Policy. If you do not wish to provide the requested Personal Data or if you do not agree to have us use the information for the purposes identified, it is your responsibility to decline to use of those Skillcrush Services for which the Personal Data is sought. You can access a limited amount of Skillcrush Services without providing us with any Personal Data. However, certain Skillcrush Services do require that you provide some amount of Personal Data. For example, and without limitation, Users who wish to to take the tutorial and project steps may be required to provide varying amounts of Personal Data. When you submit Personal Data to us, we may add it to our database. Personal Data may also be disclosed to Skillcrush employees, independent contractors, corporate partners and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve the Skillcrush Services.

From time to time, Skillcrush may also use your first name when reproducing, publishing or distributing User submitted content (in whole or in part) for use in connection with or related to the Skillcrush Services.

You can request to review, change, update or delete Personal Data that you have previously submitted to us. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before we grant you access to your Personal Data and comply with your request. Please be aware that even after such a request is processed, Skillcrush may, for a time, retain residual information about you in our backup and/or archival copies of our database.

Certain Skillcrush Services may require payment by credit card. Skillcrush partners with authorize.net to process all credit card information. Authorize.net will maintain all information provided to it in accordance with its own Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of authorize.net, which may have its own privacy policies or no privacy policy at all. Further, Skillcrush is not responsible in any way in which authorize.net manages, maintains, etc. such personal information. If you decide to leave the Skillcrush Services and access authorize.net applications, software or content, you do so at your own risk and you should be aware that our Terms and Privacy Policy no longer govern.

### Sharing, Selling and Trading Aggregate Data Collected Online With Third Parties

Skillcrush takes the privacy of our Users very seriously. We do not sell, rent or otherwise provide your Personal Data to third parties for marketing purposes without your consent. We may however sell, share or trade Aggregate Data to third parties.

### Children and Privacy

We are concerned about the safety of children when they use the Internet, and understand that children may not understand all the provisions of our Privacy Policy or make informed decisions about the choices that are made available to adult users of the Skillcrush Services. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time with their children online and to be familiar with the sites their children visit. The Skillcrush Services are not directed to children under the age of 13. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has provided Personal Data, we will comply with Children’s Online Privacy and Protection Act (“COPPA”) to delete the information or obtain verifiable parental consent in accordance with COPPA.

### International Transmission of Data

The Internet is a global environment. Using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. This means that your information may be transferred to and maintained on computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. By using the Skillcrush Services and/or communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree to our processing of your Personal Data in this manner, and agree to be bound by the applicable privacy laws that Skillcrush is governed by as well as the jurisdiction and venue provisions of the Skillcrush Terms.

### Contact Us

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy or the information collection and dissemination practices of this Website, please contact us at: [hello@skillcrush.com](mailto:hello@skillcrush.com).

### Collection and Sharing of Aggregate Data

Aggregate Data is information that does not personally identify you such as frequency of visits to the Skillcrush Site, page views, Skillcrush Services most frequently accessed, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, referrer addresses, where your computer is routing from, your browser type and version, or your operating system and platform (“Aggregate Data”). We use Aggregate Data to help us develop and improve the Skillcrush Services overall.

**Cookies.** Cookies are pieces of information that websites transfer to your computer’s web browser for storage on your computer’s hard drive. Skillcrush uses cookies on the Skillcrush Site. A cookie will remain on your hard drive even after you leave a given website and close your browser. When you return to the same website that placed the cookie on your hard drive, the website may then access the cookie.

Skillcrush uses cookies for the purpose of distinguishing your browser as a previous visitor to the Skillcrush Site by tracking repeat visits to the Skillcrush Site by you through your IP address. Skillcrush also uses cookies to identify which parts of the Skillcrush Site is most visited by you and how much time you spend in a particular part of the Skillcrush Site. The cookie is loaded on your browser during the initial visit to the Skillcrush Site. Should you provide Skillcrush with personally identifiable information, such as your name or email address, the cookies Skillcrush uses will collect personally identifiable information. Skillcrush also collects your your IP address and a time stamp of your arrival on the Skillcrush website.

The information collected by Skillcrush through cookies is used strictly for statistical analysis of usage trends related to the Skillcrush Site. Skillcrush does not share, sell, transfer or provide any information collected through cookies to any third parties. You can set your browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you turn off cookies or refuse them, though, you may not be able to use every portion of the Skillcrush Site.

**Click-Throughs.** Skillcrush or a third-party authorized by Skillcrush, such as Mail Champ, may send email messages which use a “click-through” text or graphic link that will take you to content on the Skillcrush Site. The third-party provider’s own terms of use and privacy policy will apply to your use of click-throughs. When you click on this link, you pass through our web server before arriving at the destination web page. If we use this feature, we will track click-through data to help determine our users’ interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. The third party provider may collect anonymous information about your use of the GPTMC Services. The third party reports the anonymous data that they collect on our behalf back to us, which we may link to your personally identifiable information. When we link this information, it is treated under the Privacy Policy as Personal Data. If you prefer not to be tracked by using click-throughs by either Skillcrush or a third-party authorized by Skillcrush, do not click text or graphic links in the email.

**Advertising.** The Skillcrush Site may contain advertisements provided by third party advertisers (each an “Advertiser”). An Advertiser may place or utilize its own cookie on your browser, and may collect Aggregate Data about your visit to the Skillcrush Site, including but not limited to the number of times you viewed an advertisement. If an Advertiser requests that you provide any Personal Data, that Advertiser’s use and collection of the information will be governed by the Advertiser’s own privacy policy, and not our Privacy Policy. We recommend that you review any Advertiser’s privacy policy before providing Personal Data.

### Disclosures Required by Law

It is possible that we may need to disclose Personal Data when required by law, such as responses to civil or criminal subpoenas, or other requests by law enforcement personnel, to establish or exercise our legal rights or, defend against legal claims and if in our judgment in such circumstances disclosure is required or appropriate.

We may also share Personal Data if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms, or as otherwise required by law.
